<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
         xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
   <rdf:Description>
      <dc:title>The American Occupation of the Philippines: 1898–1912</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>James Henderson Blount (1869–1918)</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Project Gutenberg, Urbana, Illinois, USA., 2011-06-28</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2011-06-28</dc:date>
      <dc:rights>This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this eBook or online at www.gutenberg.org.
This eBook is produced by the Online Distributed Proofreading Team at www.pgdp.net.
James Henderson Blount (1869–1918) was a US judge who went in to the Philippines as a volunteer shortly after the US took over this colony from Spain. After his experiences, he became critical of the US policy in the Philippines, and urged for an early independence of the country.
The American Occupation of the Philippines, 1898–1912 (first published in 1912) is a critical work on the American rule in the Philippines. This work is much criticized by Dean Worchester in his book, The Philippines, Past and Present (1914), also present in Project Gutenberg. The latter was only returning the favor, as Dean Worcester receives in this work a full chapter of harsh criticism.
This book is prepared from scans of the first edition, available at the Internet Archive: 1, 2, 3.
However, the illustrations, including the scan of the title page have been taken from scans of the second edition from 1913: 1.



</dc:rights>
      <dc:description>Written by an American judge who served in the Philippines in the early years of the American occupation of the islands, this book is highly critical of the American rule. In particular Dean C. Worcester is characterized as the direst calamity since the occupation.</dc:description>
      <dc:identifier>pg:36542</dc:identifier>
   </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
